

Xannealia Brown

M/WBE Coordinator

Years of Experience

Bio

Xannealia is a highly skilled and dedicated professional with experience in multiple facets of construction compliance (minority companies), human resources, and office administration. She is extremely focused, with a strict attention to detail and accuracy; an excellent oral and written communicator; is flexible, with the ability to multi-task and achieve lean staffing; and a strong advocate of positive change and new ideas.

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

Halmar International, LLC | Nanuet, NY | 09-2019 - Present

MTA-LIRR, Third Track Expansion | Floral Park Queens to Hicksville Long Island, NY | \$1.825B M/WBE/SDVOB Specialist | 09/2019 – 04/2022

M/WBE/SDVOB Specialist for this complex installation of 10 miles of additional track to complete a continuous new third Main Line track, including the construction of 19 bridges (14 railroad bridges and five roadway bridges), seven passenger stations, two parking garages and 250,000 sf of retaining walls. As the work affects LIRR railroad operations, Halmar's team developed innovative concepts for bridges and underpasses that required only 25% of the anticipated weekend outages. Accelerated Bridge Construction (ABC) techniques were employed using Self-Propelled Modular Transporters (SPMTs) for four bridge replacements and box-jacking for constructing seven bridges. This allowed for significant track outage reduction. For example, during a single weekend, the existing bridge was demolished, new precast seats, backwalls and bearings were installed, and a new bridge was moved into place using the SPMT. For underpasses, the railroad bridge substructure was cast in a pit in a temporary location, the superstructure erected on top and then the bridge was jacked into place during one single weekend double track outage (rather than three weeks of outage). This is the first time this technique has been used in the United States. Additional innovations included modified staging to eliminate property takings and the use of modular retaining walls to eliminate all private property acquisitions and significantly reduce tree clearing by reducing the ROW footprint.

Xannealia's responsibilities included:

- Developing and maintaining a central repository for MBE, WBE and SDVOB site visit reports, CUF reports, workforce reports and the necessary documentations and effort required for reporting firm participation on the project
- Meeting with Purchasing, procurement, and Construction departments on a weekly basis to discuss the monitoring and reporting of utilization on the project and ensure participation is in consideration of the requirements
- Monitoring and reporting on a weekly, monthly, quarterly, semi-annual, and annual basis the results of MBE,
 WBE and SDVOB subcontract utilization and workforce utilization
- Responding to all field questions and concerns relating to the project's MBE, WBE and SDVOB requirements
 and keeping a detailed log of both the questions and responses
- Keeping current with diversity best practices and representing the JV in commercial networking events and forms



D/M/WBE Compliance Coordinator | 12/2014 - 09/2019

- Assist with the bid and proposal process
- Monitor strict compliance with EEO and 16 Step Affirmative Action on each active contract
- Conduct monthly meetings with contracts to review progress in meeting the contractual goals and identify any issues with minority Subcontractors and staff
- Attend management meetings with various Owners to discuss the progress of our contracts (i.e., MTA)
- Monitor strict adherence to policies and procedures
- Assist D/M/WBE Compliance Officer and Field Engineers with the process of closing out contracts
- Track documents submitted by subcontractors and field personals on a weekly/monthly basis (i.e., Cuff/Affidavit forms, Union, and Sub letters)
- Work with numerous minority companies on various contract to ensure their participation on government-related contracts (i.e., MTA PANYNJ and NYC&NYS DOT), such as:
 - Systems facilities Caverns and Track (CS179) \$564M
 - GCT Station Caverns & Track (CM007) \$655M
 - Mid- Day Storage Yard Facility (CQ033) \$293M
 - Harold 3 MTA contract (CH057) \$79M
 - City Island Bridge (HBX1164) \$107M
 - Henry Hudson (HH-89) \$82M
 - Newark Airport (Terminal 1) \$1.3B
 - Verrazano Narrows (375- VN) \$34M

EDUCATION

B.S. in Health Science, Mercy College (Bronx, NY), May 2011

WORK HISTORY

Halmar (M/WBE Coordinator): 09/2019 - Present

Tutor Perini Corporation (D/M/WBE Compliance Coordinator): 12/2014 - 09/2019

PROJECT CATEGORY EXPERIENCE

Amtrak Experience Bridge Construction MTA/LIRR Experience NYSDOT PANYNJ

Skills

Microsoft Word/Excel/Outlook Databases Internet Research